ecometro.com 2015-12-11

# Privacy — Chinook Book

## Celilo Group Media Privacy Policy

**Effective Date** : June 10, 2015 

Celilo Group Media, Inc. (“Celilo”) cares about your privacy. Celilo will limit the amount of Personal Information (defined below) it asks of you to what is stated in this Privacy Policy, and Celilo will treat such Personal Information according to this policy. This Privacy Policy outlines the types of Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information (defined below) that is collected by Celilo from consumers and how we use and protect it. This Privacy Policy also tells you what to do if you do not want Celilo to use your Personal Information to market its services to you, and how you can change information you have already provided to us. This Privacy Policy applies to the data collected through your use of chinookbook.net and/or through your use of our Chinook Book app, and to Celilo’s collection of data through responses to printed promotional materials, telephone calls to Celilo, and other offline contacts we may have with you. 

### 1\. Your Agreement to this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy informs you about our information collection, use, and disclosure practices. Throughout this Privacy Policy, unless otherwise specifically indicated, when we say “use of our Chinook Book app and/or chinookbook.net” (or a similar phrase), this “use” includes visiting and browsing chinookbook.net, downloading and using the app, and/or providing your Personal Information to us through chinookbook.net, the app, and/or through offline contacts. When you use the app and/or chinookbook.net, you signify that you have read, understand, and agree to the terms of our current Privacy Policy, and to our collection, use, and dissemination of your Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with any term in this Privacy Policy, do not download or use the app and do not use chinookbook.net. If you choose not to provide Personal Information, you may not be able to do certain things through the app or on chinookbook.net. You agree that this Privacy Policy is supported by reasonable and valuable consideration (which consideration includes your use of the app and/or chinookbook.net), and you acknowledge your receipt of and the sufficiency of the consideration. 

### 2\. Intended Users of our Mobile App and Website

Our Chinook Book app and chinookbook.net are intended for adults only. By downloading and using the app and/or by using chinookbook.net, you affirm that (i) you are at least eighteen (18) years old, or that you are between the ages of thirteen (13) and seventeen (17) and possess legal parental or guardian consent to use the app and chinookbook.net, and to provide Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information to us; and (ii) you have authority to agree to this Privacy Policy and are competent and capable of understanding, agreeing to, and complying with this Privacy Policy. Our Chinook Book app and chinookbook.net are not directed to children under age 13, and children under age 13 are prohibited from using our app and chinookbook.net. We do not knowingly (i) collect information from anyone under age 13; (ii) permit submission of information by anyone under age 13; (iii) contact children under age 13 for marketing purposes; or (iv) sell products or services to children under age 13. If we learn that we have received information from a child under age 13 in violation of this Privacy Policy, we will use that information only to respond directly to that child (or a parent or legal guardian of that child) to inform him or her that he or she cannot use the app or chinookbook.net, and subsequently, we will delete that information from our files. 

### 3\. What kind of information do we collect and store?

**(a) Your Personal Information**

In order to download the Chinook Book app, to register for an account through and to use the app, to purchase a Chinook Book through chinookbook.net, and/or to participate in certain other services provided by Celilo, you will be asked to provide Personal Information. **You are never under any obligation to provide such information.** If you choose not to provide us Personal Information, you can still browse chinookbook.net; however, you will not be able to purchase a Chinook Book, use the app, or use certain other services offered by Celilo. When you do provide us with Personal Information, you are authorizing us to use that information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy and to store your information on our servers located in the United States. 

Personal Information includes the following categories of information: 

  1. Contact Data, including your name, email address, physical address, home and/or mobile phone numbers, other information that could be used to contact you or identify you personally, and your password used to create an account on the Chinook Book app; 
  2. Credit card information; and 
  3. Other information you actively enter into the app and/or chinookbook.net, or otherwise provide to us through offline contacts, such as email, letter, or phone call. 

**(b) Automatically-collected information we receive from your use of our Chinook Book app and/or chinookbook.net**

When you use the Chinook Book app and/or chinookbook.net, we automatically collect and store the following categories of information (hereinafter referred to as “Automatically-Collected Information”). Unless otherwise specifically stated in this Privacy Policy, Automatically-Collected Information may be combined with Personal Information you provide to us. We automatically collect and store the following types of information when you use the Chinook Book app: 

  1. Your mobile device and network identifiers, such as MAC or IP addresses; 
  2. Your mobile device's unique device ID; 
  3. Geo-Location Data: Our app doesn't work without geo-location data. We use both precise geo-location data and very non-precise, general market location (i.e. a major metropolitan area, like Portland) in different ways to provide both an optimal app experience while respecting your privacy. We only record your precise geo-location when you set up an account, redeem a coupon or when you go into offline mode. We use your precise geo-location every time you use the app to identify the market you are in and display merchants near you. We record your general location whenever you use the app. There is an optional setting in the app that will send you a push notification when you are near a merchant you have designated as a Favorite. For this service to work we use your precise geo-location in the background at all times and send you a push notification when our system has determined you are likely nearby a Favorite merchant. When you have this setting enabled we will also record your precise location when you enter, stay in and exit the geofence around a Favorite merchant. 

We collect this data so we can aggregate all of our user geo-location data and provide only the de-identified and aggregated coupon redemption data to merchants for their analysis so they can, for example, determine how often a coupon is redeemed at a given store location. We do NOT provide your specific geo-location data along with your identity to any third party; rather, we only provide the aggregated redemption data to our merchants; The following data is de-identified and aggregated to provide data for both internal analysis and reporting to our merchants: 

  4. Your coupon history, including purchases, unlocks, redemptions, favorites, and savings; 
  5. Domain server; 
  6. Type of mobile device accessing the app; 
  7. Type of operating system your mobile device uses; 
  8. Date and time you access the app and date and time you use the app to redeem specific coupons; 
  9. Amount of time you spend on each app feature; 
  10. Order in which you view the app features and pages, and the order in which you take actions in the app; and 
  11. Other similar information about the interaction between your browser and the app. 

We automatically collect and store the following types of information when you use chinookbook.net: 

  1. Your MAC addresses or IP addresses; 
  2. Domain server; 
  3. Type of computer and web browser used to access chinookbook.net; 
  4. Type of operating system your computer uses; 
  5. Date and time you access chinookbook.net; 
  6. Referring source, _i.e.,_ the website you used to access chinookbook.net; 
  7. Amount of time you spend on each chinookbook.net page and feature you use; 
  8. Order in which you view the features and pages on chinookbook.net, and the order in which you take actions on chinookbook.net; and 
  9. Other similar information about the interaction between your browser and chinookbook.net. 

**(c) Information we do NOT collect:** When you use our Chinook Book app or Chinookbook.net, we do **NOT** (i) track your activity across multiple applications or websites, and we do not allow targeted advertising based on your activity across multiple applications or websites; (ii) access or store your contacts, call logs, calendar appointments, text messages, photos, videos, or other information stored on your mobile device; (iii) access or store your usernames or passwords (other than that which you use to set up your account through the Chinook Book app), such as username and passwords for your Facebook, Twitter, or other social network or email accounts; (iv) share your information with social networks, advertising networks, or other third parties for their own marketing or other independent purposes. In order to provide the services offered through the app, however, the app may interact with some features of your mobile device, such as your email account, but all of this processing occurs on your mobile device itself, and this information is not transferred through the app to us. 

### 4\. Cookies and Web Beacons

We collect Automatically-Collected Information through commonly-used information gathering tools, such as cookies and web beacons.   
**(a) Cookies:** To help make the Chinook Book app and chinookbook.net more responsive to the needs of our users, we may use a standard feature found in browser software, called a "cookie" to assign each visitor a unique, random number, a sort of anonymous user ID that resides in your mobile device if you use the app and in your computer hard drive if you use chinookbook.net. Standing alone, cookies do not identify the Personal Information of the user; rather, they identify the mobile device that a user uses to access the app, or they identify the computer that a user uses to access chinookbook.net. A cookie cannot read data off of your hard drive or mobile device. Cookies may store user preferences, information about your browser, list of app and/or chinookbook.net features used, and activities conducted while using the app and/or chinookbook.net. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but, at your option, expense, and responsibility, you can block cookies at any time by changing the preferences in your browser and/or delete cookies from your hard drive and mobile device. By blocking and deleting cookies, however, you may not have access to the entire set of features of the app or chinookbook.net and features may not function properly. Generally, we use cookies to customize your experience while using the app and chinookbook.net. When you use the app to create an account, we use cookies to store your username so you do not have to re-enter it each time you want to access your account. Further, if you have an account through the app, cookies containing encrypted information allow us to uniquely identify you when you are logged into your account. Cookies enable us to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. We may use cookies to remember your personal settings, pre-fill forms for you by saving your preferences for future visits, and compile aggregate data about user traffic on and user interaction with the app and chinookbook.net so we can offer better experiences and tools in the future.   
**(b) Web Beacons:** We may also use "web beacons" to collect Automatically-Collected Information about your use of the Chinook Book app and/or chinookbook.net, and your viewing and use of emails we send to you. Web beacons are graphic image files imbedded in a web page, app feature, or email that provide a presence on such web page, feature, or email and send back to its home server information from the user's browser. The information collected by web beacons allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using the app and chinookbook.net and opening our emails, and for what purposes. For example, we might place a web beacon in a marketing email to notify us when a user clicks on the link in the email. We do not collect Personal Information with web beacons, and we do not link information retrieved from web beacons directly with Personal Information you've given us. 

### 5\. How We Use Your Information

**(a) Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information**

When you supply us with your Personal Information, we will use it for the express purpose stated when we ask for such Personal Information ( _e.g.,_ we use your Personal Information to fulfill any transaction you initiate, such as the purchase of a Chinook Book), to respond to any requests you may have about use of the Chinook Book app or chinookbook.net, to contact you regarding your account or your use of the app or chinookbook.net, and to provide required notices. 

**Credit card information:** We use your credit card information to fulfill purchase orders you initiate. We provide data encryption during the entire payment process. We will only use your credit card information to charge you for a Chinook Book or Full Access subscription if specifically ordered by you. 

If you use the Chinook Book app to order a Full Access Subscription, we use a third-party intermediary to manage credit card payment processing. We only share your credit card information with this third-party intermediary, your credit card provider, and our banking partners, to process payments. We provide an auto-renew feature that will automatically renew your Full Access Subscription. We will provide a notice at least one week prior to the auto-renew occurring to remind you that you are about to be charged and what the amount charged will be. If this feature is enabled, our third-party intermediary will store your credit card information, but this third-party can only use your credit card information to process payments for your purchase of a Full Access Subscription. If you disable this auto-renew feature, our third-party intermediary will not store your credit card information and will delete it. Because we collect credit card information (and because it’s generally a good idea), we recommend that you lock your mobile device. If you lose your mobile device or if it is stolen, we recommend that you immediately contact your mobile device carrier to have the device and the Chinook Book app disabled. We shall have no responsibility or liability to pay for any unauthorized or fraudulent transactions. 

**IP Addresses:** We use IP/MAC addresses to track and aggregate Automatically-Collected Information. We also collect IP/MAC addresses and mobile device IDs from our app users when they log into their accounts in order to confirm the applicable user's identity. 

**Your coupon history, including purchases, unlocks, redemptions, favorites and savings:** For app users, we store coupon history information on our server so the app can be deleted from your device without losing coupons, favorites, or savings. This allows coupon account information to be transferred to new devices, such as a replacement or upgraded device. 

**Other Uses of Your Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information:** We may use your Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information to customize and tailor your experience using the app and/or chinookbook.net, displaying content we think you might be interested in and according to your preferences (but we do not track your activity across multiple websites or mobile applications for the purposes of serving targeted advertising to you). 

We may use Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information to help diagnose problems with the app and chinookbook.net , to make the app and chinookbook.net more compatible with the technology used by our users, to analyze statistical use patterns, and to otherwise improve our app and chinookbook.net. For example, we may use Automatically-Collected Information to track what our users look at most so we can recognize and provide more of the desired features. 

We also use Automatically-Collected Information to determine which website referred you to chinookbook.net and as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy. 

**(b) Marketing Communications:** We may use your Contact Data to provide you information about other products or services that may be of interest to you (including those we may offer jointly with other companies). We may also send your mobile device notifications from time to time to alert you to new coupons or new available versions of the app. We will never share your Contact Data with any third party for their own marketing or other independent uses. If we use your Contact Data to send marketing communications to you, we will provide you with an easy mechanism to opt-out of receiving future marketing communications (see Section 7(a) below for more information). If you request that we not contact you for marketing purposes (either by using the opt-out mechanism or contacting us), we reserve the right to contact you for non-marketing purposes relating to your account or other use of the app or chinookbook.net. We respect your privacy and your right to limit the ways in which we contact you. 

### 6\. Sharing your information:

Except in the circumstances described in this Privacy Policy, Celilo does not share, sell, rent, license, trade, or otherwise transfer or disclose your Personal Information or Automatically-Collected Information with or to any third parties for their promotional purposes or otherwise. 

**(a) Merchants:** From time to time, we share de-identified and aggregated coupon redemption data (including the date, time, and location of redemptions) and favorite coupon data with our merchants to help them improve their offers. We share this aggregated, anonymous redemption information with merchants to help them track redemptions. Celilo will never give merchants Contact Data, specific device information, network identifiers, or information that personally identifies you. 

**(b) Third-Party Service Providers:** We share Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information with our third-party service providers who assist us by performing services related to our operation of the Chinook Book app or chinookbook.net (such as hosting, data storage, transaction processing, and security). These third-party service providers are not authorized to use your information in any way other than as described here and are required to keep the information confidential. 

**(c)Third-Party Analytics Services:** We may use third-party analytics services in connection with the Chinook Book app and chinookbook.net to assist us in better understanding our app and chinookbook.net users. For example, we use these services to track and analyze certain Automatically-Collected Information, such as feature usage. We only ever provide these service providers with (or allow these service providers to collect on our behalf) Automatically-Collected Information. The recordings will never identify you personally, though they can identify your IP/MAC addresses and mobile device IDs. We use the information collected from these service providers to find usability problems to make the app and chinookbook.net easier to use. The information we receive from these third parties may be re-associated with your Personal Information after we receive it back from these third parties. These third parties are not authorized to use your information in any other way and are required to keep the information confidential. 

**(d) Merger, Acquisition, or Sale:** We may transfer your Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information to another entity if Celilo is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or any portion of its assets or business. In this event, we will use reasonable efforts to notify you when Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information is transferred to a third party, as well as to notify you about choices you may have regarding your information (this notification may be made via email to you or by posting a prominent notice within the Chinook Book app and on chinookbook.net). Unless you consent otherwise, your Personal Information will remain subject to the promises made in this Privacy Policy, even after the transfer. But any Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information you provide after the transfer will likely be subject to a new privacy policy, and you should review that policy. 

**(e) Required by Law:** Celilo reserves the right to and will release Personal Information and/or Automatically-Collected Information, without your consent and without additional notice to you, if Celilo believes in good faith that (i) such release is required to comply with any law, rule, or regulation, or any search warrant, subpoena, court order, or similar legal process; or (ii) disclosure is necessary to protect or enforce Celilo's rights or property, to protect the rights or property of others, to protect your safety or the safety of others, in emergency situations, to defend against legal claims, or to take action regarding illegal activities or suspected fraud. 

### 7\. Controlling Your Information; Opt-Out Rights

**(a) How can I opt out of marketing communications?**   
Marketing emails from Celilo will always include an unsubscribe link at the bottom. To opt out of marketing email, please unsubscribe using this link. Or you may contact us via the contact information shown in Section 13 to unsubscribe. 

To opt out of device notifications, disable the push notification preference inside the Chinook Book app. 

**(b) Stop Future Collection of Information:** You can stop all future collection of Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information that is collected through your use of chinookbook.net by discontinuing use of the website (but see below regarding data retention of earlier-collected data). You can stop all future collection of Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information that is collected through your use of the Chinook Book app by uninstalling the app (but see below regarding data retention of earlier-collected data). You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network. Please note that we will not be notified if you uninstall the app or discontinue use of the website. If you want us to remove your Personal Information from our records, please see the paragraph below. 

**(c) Review and Modification of Information; Deleting Your Information:** You can review or modify the Personal Information you have included in your Chinook Book app account or change your password by logging in and accessing your account, or by contacting us at mobileservices@chinookbook.net. Please note that your account and all features of the app may not function properly if we remove any or all of your Personal Information. If you want to close your app account and/or ask us to delete your information from our databases (whether such information was provided through the app or through chinookbook.net), please contact us at mobileservices@chinookbook.net. But we will not be notified if you merely uninstall the app, and we will not know that you want us to remove your information from our databases. Upon receipt of your request, Celilo will use commercially-reasonable efforts to delete your account and remove your Personal Information from our databases; however, it may be impossible to remove residual Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information, such as information tracked in our web server log files and information that may reside in backup files. This residual information is retained to preserve the integrity of backed-up files and for business continuity purposes. Further, we may retain Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information to comply with our retention policy described in Section 8 below. 

### 8\. Retention and Storage

See Section 5(a) above regarding our retention of your credit card information that you provide to complete purchases you initiate through the Chinook Book app or chinookbook.net. We will retain all other Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information in our databases until you contact us and ask that we remove your information from our databases. Please note that it may be impossible to remove some Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information, such as information tracked in our web server log files and information that may reside in backup files. We may also retain Automatically-Collected Information even after you request that we remove your information from our databases, for use in the aggregate and to analyze and improve the app and chinookbook.net. Further, even after you request that we remove your information from our databases, we may retain Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information in accordance with our document management and retention policy and to comply with applicable laws, rules, regulations, or guidelines; to prevent fraudulent activity; to protect ourselves against liability; to resolve disputes; to permit us to pursue available remedies and limit any damages that we may sustain. 

### 9\. Links

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through your use of the Chinook Book app and chinookbook.net. The app and chinookbook.net may contain links to other websites, products, or services that are not owned or controlled by Celilo. Celilo is not responsible or liable for the privacy practices or other actions of these third parties or their websites, products, or services. These third parties may have their own policies regarding privacy and security. We advise you to review such policies to determine what information about you may be collected and used when you visit and use these linked websites, products, or services. 

### 10\. Security of Information

We have generally-accepted industry standard physical, electronic, and procedural security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, alteration, or unauthorized access of Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information we collect and store. These safeguards include secure login authentication for accounts on the Chinook Book app, encryption during transmission with the use of Secure Sockets Layer for processing transactions securely, firewalls, and other security measures. All Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information is subject to restricted access to authorized employees and contractors who need to know the information in order to operate and improve our Chinook Book app and chinookbook.net. 

Please promptly notify us if you become aware that your Personal Information is lost, stolen, or used without permission. If you notify us of such an event, we may disable access to your app account in order to prevent an unauthorized third party from accessing your account. 

### 11\. Legal Disclaimer

We cannot guarantee that your information will never be compromised. No Internet or wireless network transmission is ever 100% secure. Further, while we employ reasonable measures to protect your information, we do not and cannot guarantee that there will be no unintended disclosures of your information or that unauthorized third parties will not defeat our security measures or use non-public information for improper purposes. Nevertheless, we value your business and have adopted this Privacy Policy and undertaken the described security measures as an endeavor to respect your privacy and to keep your information confidential. 

### 12\. Modifications to Privacy Policy

Celilo reserves the right, at any time, to change or remove this Privacy Policy at its discretion. We will post any new policy here, and you should visit this area frequently to stay informed. You can determine if this Privacy Policy has been revised since your last visit to the Chinook Book app or chinookbook.net by referring to the effective date at the top of the Privacy Policy. We will also provide notification of significant changes to this Privacy Policy through the app and on chinookbook.net. In addition, if changes are significant and if you have set up an account through the app or if you have signed up to receive our news and updates through chinookbook.net, we will also notify you of such changes either (i) via the Contact Data you have provided to us; or (ii) by requiring that you agree to the revised Privacy Policy the next time you access your account in the app. Your use of the app and/or chinookbook.net following any revision to this Privacy Policy constitutes your acceptance of and agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy, as revised by us. The revisions to this Privacy Policy will apply to all Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information collected on and after the date on which we post the revised Privacy Policy. We will keep prior versions of this Privacy Policy in an archive for your review upon your request. 

### 13\. Contact Us

Contact Celilo through any of the means listed below if you have any comments or questions about this Privacy Policy or the use of your Personal Information, or to report any violations of the Privacy Policy. To review or correct your Personal Information with Celilo, please contact Celilo through any of the means listed below and provide your full name, mailing address, and email address along with your request for review or correction.   
Contact Information:   
**Address:** Celilo Group Media, Inc., 208 SW First Ave., Suite 260, Portland, OR 97204   
**Email:** [mobileservices@chinookbook.net](mailto:mobileservices@chinookbook.net)   
**Phone:** 503-226-7798   
**Fax:** 503-226-7917 

Please see Sections 7(c) and 8 above regarding our retention of your information, even after you request that we change or delete your information. 

### 14\. Unenforceability

If any part of this Privacy Policy is determined to be invalid, illegal, or unenforceable, pursuant to applicable law, then the invalid, illegal, or unenforceable provision will be deemed superseded by a valid, legal, and enforceable provision that most closely matches the intent of the original provision, and the remainder of this Privacy Policy shall continue in full force and effect. 

Copyright © 2013 Celilo Group Media, Inc. All Rights Reserved.
